Stephen Trudell

steviejtrudell@gmail.com
 Austin, TX 78749
 (737) 402-0876

About

Full stack web developer leveraging over a decade of experience in audio engineering to provide creative solutions in website development and design. Recently earning a certificate from the Code Bootcamp at UT Austin, specializing in JavaScript and the MERN stack, Stephen is ready to offer excellent time management, work ethic, and attention to detail to a wide range of professional projects. Being reliable, passionate, quick to adapt, and known by colleagues as friendly and easy to work with in both large and small scale teams, as well as highly responsible and productive when working independently, Stephen is excited to advance his experience in the diverse field of web development.

Skills

Languages / Technologies

JavaScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, React, GraphQL, SQL, MongoDB, Node, Express, Bootstrap, AJAX, RESTful APIs, SEO, PWAs, SPAs, Swipe, Jest/Mocha, Git

DevOps

MERN Stack, AGILE, TDD, MVC, GitHub, Heroku

Certification 9

Full Stack Web Development

The University of Texas at Austin - 2022

Projects

Project Title: Travel Diary

https://afternoon-harbor-62644.herokuapp.com/

- A web application that hosts user made blog posts detailing travel stories and tips, featuring search and save functionality.
- Developed by a team of 4, my role was primarily creating the server and REST API using Node and Express, and displaying data to the pages using Handlebars.
- This app was built with a MVC design, utilizing a SQL database, Bootstrap/CSS for the front-end, Node/Express for the back-end, and is deployed to Heroku.

Experience

2010 - Present

Audio Engineer / Musician / Producer Various - Austin, TX

- Recording, mixing, mastering, and producing audio with DAW software, including Pro Tools, Ableton Live, Print Music, and various processing plug-ins.
- Working in chaotic and radid fire production/performance settings, both in the studio and on stage.
- Intuition in finding creative solutions to unrehearsed problems.

2013 - Present

Cashier / Food Prep / Driver The Soup Peddler - Austin, TX

- Self-sufficiency and a strong work ethic developed in a small workforce within a small company.
- Administering customer service skills and time management techniques in a restaurant environment.

2006 - 2013

Cashier

H-E-B Groceries - Bee Cave, TX

 Customer service and team work skills developed in a large workforce within a large company.

References: Available upon request.

PORTFOLIO ▶ https://strudelandcoffee.github.io/react-portfolio

♠ https://github.com/strudelAndCoffee

https://www.linkedin.com/in/stevie-trudell-atx

Education

A.A. In Foreign Language: French

Austin Community College - 2013